Guide to the Hollin Hills Civic Association records, 1950-2013
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Civic Association of Hollin Hills records
1950-2013
C0231
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections and Archives.
36.5 linear feet (73 boxes)
The collection consists of publications, newsletters, photos, audiovisual materials, blueprints, and organization records (such as minutes) relating to the Hollin Hills community in Virginia.
Civic Association of Hollin Hills.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Hollin Hills Civic Association.
Historical Information
Hollin Hills is a neighborhood in Virginia. Planning for the neighborhood began in 1946 when the land was purchased by developer Robert Davenport and his associate Charles Goodman. Davenport and Goodman wanted to catch the attention of post-war homebuyers, and therefore wanted the neighborhood to be unique, a decision met with both acclaim and opposition. Families began moving into the neighborhood in 1949, and by 1957 the "Old Hollin Hills" houses were completed, as well as construction of the pool and tennis courts. The Hollin Hills Community Association was formed in 1950, and renamed the Civic Association of Hollin Hills in 1961
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of publications, newsletters, photos, audiovisual materials, and organization records (such as minutes). Also includes records of the design review committee with blueprints, plats, awards (framed and metal plaques), real estate ads, house and garden tour booklets, neighborhood phone directories, community histories in pamphlet and hard bound formats, and a bound set of newsletters 1951-1991 (ten volumes).
Series one is titled Newsletters and is dated from 1950 to 2013. The material in this series contains copies of the monthly community newsletters and bulletins, as well as ten volumes of bound newsletters.
Series two is titled 40th and 50th Anniversaries and Histories and is dated from 1985 to 1999. The material in this series relates to the community at ten, forty, and fifty years after its establishment, such as historical pamphlets. The series also contains surveys of the citizens at forty years concerning items such as hobbies, professions, and opinions, and a 50th anniversary book and material related to its publication.
Series three is titled Pool and Tennis Courts and is dated from 1952 to 2003. The material in this series includes financial and legal documents concerning the pool and tennis courts, as well as documents on construction, the use of the facilities by teams or by membership, and newsletters to the community regarding membership.
Series four is titled Community Organization and is dated from 1951 to 2006. This series contains awards, assessments and reassessments, and legal files, as well as documents pertaining to finances and taxes, history, community involvement such as the newcomer reception, property and parkland, and community and traffic safety. It also contains reports and records from the community board meetings.
Series five is titled Design Review and is dated from 1956 to 2010. This series has miscellaneous documents, guidelines and code information, correspondence, and small blueprints, as well as proposals and analyses regarding construction done to specific neighborhood homes. It also contains magazine and newspaper articles about the neighborhood houses.
Series six is titled News Clippings and Miscellaneous Records and is dated from 1951 to 2012. This series consists of newspaper and magazine clippings regarding the architecture, people, and events such as the anniversaries or house and garden tours of Hollin Hills. It also contains architecture plans and small maps of the neighborhood layout and surrounding area. The series also holds miscellaneous records such as telephone numbers, manuals for neighborhood residents, and a babysitting record book, as well as real estate advertisements found in newspapers and post cards.
Series seven is titled House and Garden Tours and Other Events and is dated from 1953 to 2012. This series contains photographs, brochures, publicity information, scripts, and other documents concerning the house and garden tours put on by Hollin Hills residents. It also contains records of publications and questionnaires about Hollin Hills resident artists, records of Fourth of July picnics, and invitations and documents from community balls and galas.
Series eight is titled Directories and is dated from 1950 to 2012. This series contains directories with lists of Hollin Hill residents' addresses and telephone numbers, as well as miscellaneous publications regarding the community.
Series nine is titled Audio and Visual Material and is dated from 1970 to 1999. This series is composed of photographs and photographic slides, cassettes, floppy disks with community information such as directories and bylaws, and VHS tapes of celebrations, flooding, residents, interviews, and other events in the community.
Series ten is titled Oversize and is dated from 1959-2009. This series is composed of a ledger, an addendum, and a 50th anniversary book layout. It also contains blueprints regarding neighborhood layout, pool construction and layout, and design review and construction on individual homes.
Arrangement
This collection organized into ten series.
Series 1: Newsletters, 1950-2013 (boxes 1-28)
Series 2: 40th and 50th Anniversaries and Histories, 1985-1999 (boxes 29-31)
Series 3: Pool and Tennis Courts, 1952-2003 (boxes 31-36)
Series 4: Community Organization, 1951-2006 (boxes 36-50, 65)
Series 5: Design Review, 1956-2010 (boxes 50-58)
Series 6: News Clippings and Miscellaneous Records, 1951-2012 (boxes 1, 58-60)
Series 7: House and Garden Tours and Other Events, 1953-2012 (boxes 60-64)
Series 8: Directories, 1950-2012 (boxes 66-68)
Series 9: Audio and Visual Material, 1970-1999 (boxes 68-71)
Series 10: Oversize, 1959-2009 (boxes 72-73)
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds other collections on other Virginia neighborhoods, including documents on the development of the Reston area, as well as collections on United States and international planned communities.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Civic Association of Hollin Hills.
Subjects:
Architecture--United States--Designs and plans.; Housing--Virginia--Fairfax County.; Planning--Virginia, Northern.
Geographical Names:
Hollin Hills (Va.)
Contents List
- Series 1: Newsletters, 1950-2013; (Boxes 1-28)
  The material in this series contains copies of the monthly community newsletters and bulletins.
  - Newsletters, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1985-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1986-1991 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Nov. 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1988-1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1990-1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1995 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1993-1996 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1995-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 2012 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 2012-2013 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters - Various Years, 1968-1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1951-1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Bound copy of newsletters
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1955-1958 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1959-1963 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins Scanned For Book, 1952-1998 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1967-1971 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1975-1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1979-1983 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Hollin Hills Bulletin, 1988-1991 (Box 28, Folder 2)
- Series 2: 40th and 50th Anniversaries and Histories, 1985-1999; (Boxes 29-31)
  The material in this series relates to the community at ten, forty, and fifty years after its establishment, such as historical pamphlets, citizen surveys, and a fiftieth anniversary book.
  - Survey-Skills, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Fortieth Anniversary Survey, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Hollin Hills at Forty, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Hollin Hills: A History into the 4th Decade, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - 10 Years of Hollin Hills, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County History, 1992-1993 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax Chronicles, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 50th Anniversary Documents, 1949-1999 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Hollin Hills: Community of Vision (book), 1999 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - HH 50th Book: Notes, Memos,Printing, Misc., 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - 50th Book: Contents - Interior Design, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - 50th Book: First Owners - Appendices, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - 50th Publication: Memorandum - Promotional Letters, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 50th Publication: Sponsor Lists - Editorial Group, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - 50th Publication: Potential Resources - Brochures, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary Book: Contents - Community People, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary Book: Comm. Life Over Time - Bibliography, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 50th Publication, 1999 (Box 72)
- Series 3: Pool and Tennis Courts, 1952-2003; (Boxes 31-36)
  The material in this series includes financial and legal documents concerning the pool and tennis courts, as well as documents on construction, the use of the facilities, and newsletters to the community.
  - Pool Budget, 1972-1986 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - The Code of Fairfax County, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Pool Committee, Swim Team, 1954-1957, 1979-1988 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Pool Construction, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Pool Dues, 1986-1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Pool Employment/Contract/Duties, 1974-1999 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Pool Facility, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Pool Financial Documents, 1954-1984 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Pool History, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Insurance, Claims, Legal Paperwork, 1955-1987 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Pool Newsletters, 1952-1957 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Pool Newsletters, 1961-1979 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Pool Newsletters, 1980-1989 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Pool Maps, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Pool Member Correspondence/Pledges, 1954-1958 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Pool Membership, 1962-1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Pool Opening and Operating Instructions, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Pool Rules, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Pool Special Use Permit, 1988-1989 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Pool Supplies Company, 1975-1984 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Pool Committee Correspondence, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Pool Committee Legal Documents, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - CAHH Pool History, Articles of Incorporation, 1982-2004 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - CAHH Pool Loans, 1987-2003 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - CAHH Property for Pool Documents, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - CAHH Swim Club Bylaws,Committee Emails, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - CAHH Swim Club Monetary Documents, 1990-2003 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Swim Club, Proxy Votes, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Tennis Club, 1957-1968 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Tennis Courts, 1962-1969 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Tennis Leases, Agreements, Loans, 1953-1968 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Tennis Meetings, 1964-1983 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Tennis Site Plans, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Pool and Tennis Clubs, 1964-1972 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Series 4: Community Organization, 1951-2006; (Boxes 36-50, 65)
  This series contains awards, assessments, and legal files, as well as documents pertaining to finances, history, community involvement, property, and safety. It also contains records from the community board meetings.
  - Awards, 1989-1991 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Assessments, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Biondi-Hooper Legal File, 1969-1979 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Biondi-Hooper, Popkins Land Transfer, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Budgets, 1965-1997 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - CAHH Bufferstrip Easement, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 1990-1992 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - CAHH Finances, 1956-2004 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Meetings, 1989-1990, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Parks, Curbs, Gutters, 1998-2010 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Policies, 1994-1997 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - CAHH Special Events, Newcomer Reception, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Chadbourn File, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Contracts, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Database Program, 1992-1998 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Deeds, 1955-1983 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Guest Register, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Gypsy Moth, 1989-1991 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Hamilton - Fruit Basket Case, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - HeenanCase, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Historical Documents, 1953-1987 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - History, 1960-1969 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Lansburgh, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Community Documents, 1968-1991 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Community Organization Documents, 1957-1994 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Individual + Community Documents, 1952-1995 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Membership - General, Ideas, 1957-1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Neighborhood Watch Log Archives, 1994-2006 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Officer Duties and List, 1951-1998 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Operations, 1969-1972 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Opie File, 1972-1975 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Other Clubs, 1964-1969 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Parks, Bike Path, 1960-1975 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Paul Spring Drainage, 1980-1990 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Property, Merging, Land Acquisition, 1952-2006 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Prospective Members, 1967-1971 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Radon, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Randall Estates, 1975-1977 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Reassessments, 1961-1968 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Recording Secretary, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Safety, 1963-1997 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Safety and Security (VDOT), 1987-1993 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Safety and Traffic Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Stockholders, 1961-1963 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - School Paths, Purchases, 1959-1972, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Storm Sewer Easement, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Taxes, 1971-1972, 1982-1987 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Taxes - Real Estate, 1986-1988 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Tennis Courts, Rules, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Traffic Safety, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer Documents, 1951-1959 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Underground, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Woodlawn/Boswell Extension, 1978-1990 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Zoning, 1951-1957, 1973-1977 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Zoning Lobbying, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - CAHH Correspondence, 1966, 1980-1992 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Correspondence, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - CAHH Board Minutes, 1966-1987 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - CAHH Board Minutes, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - CAHH By-Laws, 1955-1962 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - CAHH By-Laws, 1961-1964 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - CAHH By-Laws, 1965-1969 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - CAHH By-Laws, 1976, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - CAHH Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - CAHH Articles of Incorporation, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - CAHH-HHCA Parcels, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Board Meetings Announcements, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Board Meeting Documents, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - CAHH General Meetings, 1992-1994 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Board Meetings Jan.-June, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Board Meetings Jul.-Dec., 1993 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 1994-1997 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - CAHH Board Meetings, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Board Documents, 1952-1956, 1973-1976 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - CAHH Extra Documents, 1989-1990 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - CAHH Paperwork, 1991-1992 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - CAHH President, 1980-1992 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - CAHH Share Certificates, 1951-1960 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - HHCA History Archives, 1989-1994 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - HHCA Neighborhood Watch, 1989-1995 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Mount Vernon Council of Citizens' Associations, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Recreation Records Certificate of Incorporation-Minutes, 1950-1962 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Recreation Records Membership-Communication, 1950-1962 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Assessment Data, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Assessment Data, 1991-1992 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Assessment Data, 1993-1994 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Assessment Data, 1995 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Assessment Data, 1996 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Compiled Assessment Data, 1966-1996 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Reassessment Data, 2006 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Ledgers, 1959 (Box 72)
- Series 5: Design Review, 1956-2010; (Boxes 50-58)
  This series has miscellaneous documents, guidelines and code information, correspondence, and small blueprints, as well as proposals regarding construction done to specific homes. It also contains magazine and newspaper articles about the neighborhood.
  - Design Review Agendas, 2003-2006 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Design Review Agendas, Proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Design Review Architecture + Process Committees, 1988-2008 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Design Review Blueprints, 1971-2009 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Design Review Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Design Review Decals, Certificates, Spreadsheets, Energy Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Freyja Residence - Design Review Committee, Oct. 2001 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Design Review Guidelines, Codes Info, Zoning, 1990-2000 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Design Review Maps, Rehobeth, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Design Review Minutes, 1996-2002 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Design Review Robert Fisher Documents, 1978, 1990-2002 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - 7200-7222 Beechwood Road, 1997-2008 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - 2403-2412 Brentwood Place, 2005-2008 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - 2400-2406 Daphne Lane, 1998-2009 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - 7801-7803 Davenport Street, 1996-2001 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - 1805-1808 Drury Lane, 1996-2003 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - 1809-1812 Drury Lane, 1997-2008 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - 1816 Drury Lane, 2006-2008 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - 1819 Drury Lane, 1997-2007 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - 2402-7520 Elba Road, 1996-2009 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - 7521-7702 Elba Road, 1996-2009 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - 7704-7809 Elba Road, 1996-2009 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - 2205-2403 Glasgow Road, 2002-2009 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - 7422-7423 Hopa Court, 1996-2002 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - 2305-2320 Kimbro Street, 1996-2009 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - 1912-1924 Martha's Road, 1997-2009 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - 1908-1951 Martha's Road, 2000-2005 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - 1974-2203 Martha's Road, 1996-2009 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - 2203-2219 Martha's Road, 2003-2009 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - 2214 Mason Hill Drive, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - 2410 Nemeth Court, 2007 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - 2320-2403 Nordok Place, 2006-2008 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - 1901-2207 Paul Spring Road, 1996-2009 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - 2101-2104 Pickwick Lane, 2003 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - 2106-2111 Popkins Lane, 2006-2008 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - 2113-2204 Popkins Lane, 1996-2009 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - 7414-7511 Range Road, 2002-2008 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - 7102-7207 Rebecca Drive, 2002-2008 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - 7215-7427 Rebecca Drive, 1996-2009 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - 7406-7410 Recard Lane, 1996-2008 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - 7300-7318 Rippon Road, 1996-2008 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - 7422 Saville Court, 2006 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - 7305-7316 Stafford Road, 1997-2009 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - 2111-2205 White Oaks Drive, 2002-2008 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Design Review Committee-Burns Correspondence,Files, 1988-1989 (Box 56, Folder 7)